Xiaoning, have a seat.
筱柠姐坐啊
Come on.
快点我们吃饭
OK.
好
Mr Ji,
纪老师
what's with the
脖子上的划痕
scratch on your neck?
怎么回事啊
Do you have a girlfriend now?
是不是有女朋友了
It's from my cat.
家里的小猫挠的
They say
人家说
single men who raise cats are
单身男人养猫
pretty much like being in a relationship.
就跟情侣差不多
Dig in.
吃饭
Which type of chopsticks should we get?
筷子买哪一种啊
Which type are you used to?
你习惯用哪种
I can use any of them.
我都可以
Then let's go with the bamboo ones.
那咱们用那种竹子的吧
They are eco-friendly, lighter and
绿色环保
heat-resistant compared to metal ones.
比金属的也轻便阻热
They also don't contain high polymer
还没有塑料的
chemical agents, unlike the plastic ones.
高分子化学制剂
Sounds good.
好
It seems that even an elite like him
原来职场精英
has a domestic side.
也有这么人夫的一面
Just park
一会儿就
over there.
停在前面那儿吧
I'll walk back by myself.
我自己走过去
We were
主要是我们两个
in the same
之前不是
office building before.
在一个办公楼办公吗
I think it's better to
我觉得还是
keep a low profile.
低调一点比较好
After all, everyone knows us.
毕竟大家都认识
Why?
为什么呀
You know...
因为
what happened
我们两个
to us was sudden.
在一起的事情有点突然
I haven't figured out
我还没有想好
how to tell them.
怎么跟他们说
Just give me some more time.
你再给我点时间
You're the boss.
听你的
By the way,
对了
I checked the almanac.
我看了黄历
The next three days
最近三天
are good to get registered.
都是领证的好时候
Shall we
那
go this afternoon?
咱们今天下午过去
OK, OK.
好 好 好
Ms Rao, good morning.
静姐 早
What's going on?
怎么了
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗
The manager's position
经理的位置
is almost certainly decided.
十有八九是定了
I heard that the president
听说行长
is meeting with the
今天上午的行程
next manager this morning.
是召见下一任经理
What?
什么
Isn't Ms Rao a candidate?
那静姐怎么在这儿啊
Why is she here?
不是静姐
Not her, nor Mr Zhao.
也不是小赵哥
Then
那
who else in our department
咱们行里还有谁
has more experience than them?
比他们俩资历更深
Who is more suitable?
更适合的呀
I heard
不是一部的
it's a direct appointment.
据说是空降
They are discussing it inside.
里边正谈着呢
Who is it?
谁呀
Would it be Mr Xing from section two?
不会是二部邢总吧
God, no!
别 别这么说
We would be fine working
要是在老江手里
under Mr Jiang.
咱们还好
We could get a brief respite.
顶多算代瑞宁古塔
But if working for Mr Xing,
你要到老邢手里
there would be
那是百慕大
no hope for us at all.
没有一丝生机了
Exactly.
是啊
My fellow colleagues,
亲爱的同事们
you are all here, huh?
都在呢
Come on,
来 来
have some fruit.
请你们吃水果啊
I got up
这个
early today and
可是我今天起了个大早
freshly picked these from the orchard.
现去果园里边摘的
Have some, here,
别客气 别客气啊
come on.
来 来 来
Take one, here.
拿着 拿着
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr Zhao,
小赵
come one,
来 来
have some.
吃水果 吃水果
Thank you.
谢谢啊 邢总
Ms Rao, hey.
饶经理也在呢
Come on!
来 来 来
Join us.
吃水果 吃水果
Have some.
吃水果
Well, you're so kind,
邢总有心了
coming in so early
一大早
to warm our hearts
就来给我们拓展一部
with these.
送温暖
Thank you.
谢谢
But I don't think Mr Xing
但是我觉得我们邢总
simply being here
这风风火火的吧
just to deliver fruit.
不像是单纯来送水果的
He should have
倒像是来看看
come to see who was called in
一部有谁被行长
for the conversation.
叫去谈话了
But as you wish,
但是如你所愿
everyone is present.
人全在
Mr Rao,
饶经理
sometimes you tend to overthink.
你有时候就多心了
This conversation
行长谈的是
is about section one,
咱们一部经理候选人
what does it
跟二部
have to do with section two?
有什么关系呢
Besides,
再说
Mr Xing wouldn't be
邢总什么素质
so petty as to
怎么可能插手
meddle in other businesses.
别人家的事呢
Reaching too far
手伸太长
can easily lead to trouble.
容易闪着腰
Honestly,
要我说呀
no wonder your performance
怪不得你们一部的业绩
is lacking.
这么拉胯
Both veterans are not proactive,
两个元老都不思进取
and are giving up the position willingly.
都把位置拱手让给别人
And yet they expect
还指着
the people under them
这手底下的人
to deliver results.
能干出点什么业绩出来
Listen to me,
这要我说呀
you should just
这你们一部啊
merge with us.
就跟我们二部并了
Mr Xing,
邢总
don't forget to take the trash with you.
吃完垃圾记得带走啊
Sure, sure.
带走 带走
Hey, you're here.
小邢啊
Sir.
行长
I know you're very driven,
知道你有拼劲
but you should also leave
但也得给行里
some opportunities for
其他的骨干们
the other key members.
留点机会吧
But...
可
who else in section one is fit to lead?
可一部还有谁合适啊
Anyone more qualified than me?
还有人比我更合适吗
Then what do you think
那你觉得
of the younger generation?
年轻一辈们怎么样
Fanggang,
小赵哥
do you want me to smash it?
需要我把它碎了吗
Sure.
碎了吧
Never mind.
算了吧
Hey,
不是
I just can't wrap my head around it.
我就 想不明白啊
There's no talent within our bank, huh?
咱行里是招不着人了吗
Why do we have to settle for
非得找这么一个
such an inexperienced kid
乳臭未干的小子
as the manager?
来当经理
He's from the Compliance Dept.
内控合规部的
What else can they do
他们除了会审查
besides auditing?
还会做什么
Fanggang,
赵哥
are you OK with it?
值吗
I honestly feel upset for you.
我都替你觉得不值真的
After being diligent for years,
兢兢业业这么多年
shouldn't it finally be
怎么着得轮到
your turn?
咱们赵哥了吧
Exactly.
就是
Do your best and leave the rest to fate.
尽人事听天命
Many things
很多事吧
don't always go as planned.
事与愿违
Besides,
再说
didn't you notice
你没看
the president was backing him up?
行长对他有多维护啊
Fanggang,
小赵哥
why are you
你怎么
defending him?
还替他找补上了呢
Yeah.
是啊
Look at everyone here.
你看看在座的每一个人
Which one of us
哪个不是在
has not been struggling
形形色色的客户里
among various clients?
真刀真枪拼出来的
He wants to lead us, right?
想当经理是吧
Fine.
那可以呀
Let's see how he
咱们就看看他怎么
holds his position.
在这个位置上坐稳
He hasn't even
人家还没开始
officially started yet.
正式入职呢
However,
不过
I do think he's quite hot.
我倒觉得他长得挺帅的
That's true.
那倒是
He can be considered
算是
a nice perk for our girls.
给咱们女同事的福利
Right,
是吧
Xiaoning?
小涂
You all,
你们一个个地
don't just be sour grapes.
别吃不着葡萄说葡萄酸
If you're really capable,
你们但凡有点能耐
he wouldn't have gotten the position.
也不会被别人抢了先
What do you mean?
什么意思
I mean you're not good enough.
我意思你不行呗
Starting today,
从今天开始
just focus on your jobs.
你们都给我干点正经事
Got it!
理解
Back to work.
干正事
Let's meet up.
见一面吧
There's something I'd like to know.
我有话想问你
Hello, Mr Yao.
喂 姚主任
Yuheng.
昱恒
Regarding the audit for
针对八月份
all branches in Nanhu Province
南湖省所有分行的
in August,
审计监察工作
we're about to have
今天我们要一起
a debrief today.
做一个总结
We are all waiting for you in here.
可就差你了啊
Alright.
行
I'm on my way.
那我现在过去
Good.
好嘞
Sorry,
抱歉
I'm kind of busy today.
我今天有点忙
Can we meet
要下班之后
after work?
才有时间见面了
Busy?
忙
Busy with becoming the
忙着来拓展一部
manager of section two?
当经理吗
Have you heard?
听说了吗
Ji Yuheng from the Compliance Dept
合规部的纪昱恒
got transferred to the BDD.
被调去拓展一部了
Really?
真的啊
Isn't it still undecided?
不是还没定吗
But,
不过呀
I'm so jealous of them.
我真羡慕他们拓展部
Having such a hot stuff as their manager,
有这么帅的帅哥当领导
that's definitely
这上班的动力
a motivation for work!
都变足了吧
That's for sure.
那可不是
I heard
我听说
he's still single.
他还是单身呢
Really?
真的啊
Let's go, go.
走吧 走吧 走吧
You're done, right?
吃饱了吧
Let's go.
走吧
Everyone has the right
这每个人吧
to pursue love.
都有追求爱情的权利啊
But if you wanna trade your career
但是要用事业
for love,
换爱情
and have an office romance,
谈一场办公室恋爱的话
I think it's best to
我觉得尽早啊
ditch that love-struck mindset
还是把那个
as soon as possible.
恋爱脑砍了吧
Lay off those dramas
没事呢
with a domineering CEO falling for
别老刷霸道总裁
a Mary Sue type.
爱上我的小说桥段
For women,
女人啊
the most important thing
只有实实在在地
is to have a strong grip
把事业握在手上
on your career.
才是最重要的
But what if
那万一
the guy also has the same mindset,
霸总也是恋爱脑
and he's willing to quit the job for love?
为爱辞职呢
Go ahead and ask about what happened
那你可以去问问
to Liu Xiaoli from section two.
拓展二部的 刘晓莉
You'll find out just
看看这个概率
how unlikely that really is.
到底有多低
Then why was Liu Xiaoli the only one
那为什么只调走
who got transferred?
刘晓莉呀
One is a rookie just starting out,
一个是刚入职场的新人
the other is
另外一个是
Mr Xing's right-hand person,
邢总的左膀右臂
a key player in section two.
拓展二部的半壁江山
Isn't that obvious
谁走谁留
who stays and who leaves?
大家都心知肚明
Liu Xiaoli's lover was also
但那个刘晓莉的老公
subjected to disciplinary actions,
也被处理了
but only symbolically.
象征性的
Let's go home together after work.
晚上一起回家
What would you like to eat?
想吃什么
I'll cook for you.
我给你做
By the way,
对了
what did you want to ask me earlier?
你白天想问我什么
Let's talk about it
正好
on the way back.
路上可以聊
Don't bother.
不用了
I'm gonna my parents' place for dinner.
我回爸妈家吃
The round eggplant is firmer.
是圆茄子偏硬
The long ones are mushier.
长茄子偏软水分多
And this is a string eggplant,
还有这是线茄子
which is also moist.
水分也多
It's a variegated eggplant.
这是花茄子
Stop messing around.
别捣乱
Yuheng is a good cook, right?
小纪不是会做饭吗
His place is not far from ours.
这隔着也不远
Feel free to come back for dinner.
随时想回来吃就回来
She doesn't need to learn cooking.
不用让闺女学这个
What's the relationship
这跟小纪会不会做饭
between these?
有什么关系
I'm talking about our daughter.
我在说咱们闺女
She doesn't have to cook,
她可以不做
but she should definitely know how.
但是不能不会
She's married,
她现在结婚了
and supposed to be different.
跟以前不一样了
A married woman
结婚之后啊
must be independent.
这个女性就是要独立
She should have her own career
不仅仅要经济独立
and also manage her life well.
生活上也要独立呀
Am I right?
是吧
She needs the kind of confidence and
她得做那种不管离开谁
courage that allows her to survive
都能够活下去的
regardless of whom she lives without,
这种底气跟勇气
well,
这个里面这个
including her
这人就包括什么
parents and husband,
父母啊 丈夫
ensuring that
都包含在内了
she won't starve even
就属于她一个人的时候
when she's on her own.
她也饿不着
Dad.
爸
How do you know Ji Yuheng
你怎么知道纪昱恒
is a good cook?
会做饭的呀
Don't boys these days
男孩子现在
all know how to cook?
不都会做饭吗
So it was your guess, huh?
不是合着你猜的呀
He should know, right?
会吧
Here we go!
回来了
It smells wonderful!
好香啊
Right, amazing!
真的好香啊
Welcome back.
回来了
Dad, mom.
爸 妈
Yuheng is here.
小纪来了
I've got an eggplant salad coming up.
还差一个凉拌茄子
Dinner will be ready soon.
马上就能开饭了
Xiaoning loves
筱柠最喜欢吃
eggplant salad.
凉拌茄子了
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
How did you get in?
谁给你开的门
I had a feeling something was off.
我就说有事吧
See.
你看看
They didn't come home together.
俩人没一块回来
Yuheng even
这小纪还专门
called us saying he's coming.
打电话说他要来
Nah, everything is fine.
有什么事啊 有事
Isn't it normal
这两口子吵架
for couples to argue?
不很正常的吗
What's normal about it?
什么很正常呀
For your information,
我跟你讲啊
our daughter
咱们家筱柠
isn't someone picky.
可不是多事的人
I need to ask her about this later.
我一会儿必须得问问
It's just your imagination.
你就瞎操心
Stay out of the kids' matters.
孩子的事你少管啊
They can make it.
你让他们自己处理
You're just dodging the real issue,
你这就是逃避问题
you know.
我跟你讲
In a marriage...
婚姻里都是
Move over!
过去
It's all about the little things.
婚姻里都是以小见大的
If they're not handled properly,
这小问题不解决了
the consequences
拖时间久了
are unimaginable.
就是大毛病
Didn't you say
不是你说
you're going home for dinner?
要回爸妈家吃饭吗
So I came here as well.
所以我就来了呀
I mean...
我说回
my parents' home.
我爸妈家
Aren't your parents
你爸妈现在
mine as well?
不也是我爸妈吗
What happened today?
今天 什么情况
You wanna ask me something earlier.
上午还说要问我事
What's that?
什么事啊
Not a good time now.
我爸妈在不太方便
Let's discuss it later.
回去再说吧
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
Thanks, Yuheng.
辛苦了 小纪
Here
来
comes eggplant salad.
凉拌茄子
This is quite a spread!
太丰盛了
Alright,
来吧 咱们
let's dig in!
咱们开动吧
Come on,
来 来 来
Yuheng,
小纪啊
you've done all the hard work.
你看 你最辛苦
Here you go.
来 来 来
Let me serve you first.
先给你盛啊
OK.
好
Thanks, dad.
谢谢爸
Would you like some fish?
来点鱼
I don't eat fish.
我不吃鱼
Too many bones!
鱼刺多多呀
I prefer meat.
我喜欢吃肉
This fish
这鱼
is fresh and good for the brain.
又鲜又长脑子
You just love meat.
你偏爱吃肉
Picking bones is too much hassle.
挑刺太麻烦了
I don't like it.
不喜欢吃
Isn't it true that
不是人活着
nothing is too troublesome?
什么不麻烦啊
Compared to other major life events,
跟其他人生大事相比
eating is one of the simplest things.
吃已经是最简单的事了
If there are bones, just pick them out.
有刺那就挑出来呗
If there's a problem, just solve it.
有麻烦就解决
Right, Yuheng?
是不是 小纪
If you're not even
如果你连这个事
willing to tackle this,
都不愿意干
how are you gonna manage
那以后那么长的日子
all the long days ahead?
怎么过
You
你
seem to have some issues with me.
对我有情绪
Exactly what's going on?
到底怎么了
Let's talk after dinner.
吃完饭再说吧
Alright.
行了
You two should stop
你俩就别在
playing these tricks
我们眼皮子底下
right under our noses.
搞这些小动作了
What's really happened?
到底出什么事了
Nothing.
没出什么事
Nothing happened,
出什么事了
right?
没事吧
Mom, you love fish soup.
妈你喜欢喝鱼汤
Let me get you some.
我给你盛碗汤啊
Dad, mom,
爸 妈
actually, today,
其实今天
I've received a
我收到了一份
job offer.
新的工作邀约
I'm about...
是要调
Get burnt?
烫手了
Impossible.
烫什么手呀
It's been served for a while.
都出锅这么半天了
She couldn't possibly get burnt by it.
能烫着她吗
Yuheng,
小纪
keep going.
你继续说
- Actually, it's a transfer... - Dad.
其实是要调 爸
Um...
那个
Mr Liu
刘伯伯
just mentioned he needs to talk to you.
刚才跟我说找你有事
It just came to my mind.
我才想起来
Usually he doesn't reach out to me.
这个老刘轻易不找我
If he's looking for me,
他要找我肯定是有
it must be...
有 有 有
something important.
要 要紧的事
I've got to see him.
我 我得去一趟啊
Dad.
爸
Are you going alone?
你自己去啊
You should come with me.
你跟我一块去呀
Why should I?
我跟你一块去干吗
I was talking with Yuheng.
我跟小纪说事呢
You could talk later.
你回头再说
His family just got a dog.
老刘他们家养了一条狗
It's ferocious!
太 太凶了
When did they get a dog?
他们家什么时候养狗了
Come on, follow me.
走 走 走
- I was about to... - They just got it.
我正跟小纪说 刚养的
It's a huge dog.
好大一条狗
Aren't you gonna see your friend?
不是去找老刘吗
Forget it.
找什么老刘
Every time we meet,
找老刘
he brags about his grandson.
见面他就显摆他孙子
It drives me crazy.
我烦得慌
Look at you.
你看看
Do you even look like a father?
你有当爹的样子吗
Besides,
再说了
you're a grown man.
你一个大男人
Come on, stop it.
能听出什么来
I should
要听
do all the spying.
也是我听
Move aside.
起来
Hey.
你看
Just cut to the chase.
想说什么就直接说吧
Did you just
你刚才
plan to tell them
准备要跟他们说什么呀
that you're
是要说
assigned to the BDD
你准备调到拓展一部
as my supervisor?
当我顶头上司的事儿吗
So, you knew it.
你都知道了
It's all over the Xingcheng branch.
星城分行都传遍了
How could I not know?
我怎么会不知道
My mom used to be an accountant,
我妈她以前是做会计的
so she's quite
对这种规章制度
sensitive to these rules.
比较敏感
If you bring this up,
你跟他们说这些
don't you think they would be worried?
你觉得他们会不担心吗
But it doesn't
不过他们担不担心
really matter.
也没关系
After all, this marriage of ours
反正咱俩这段关系
will come to an end finally.
迟早都要结束
They'll find out then.
早晚都会知道
What do you mean
什么叫我们这段关系
by saying that?
迟早会结束啊
Are you saying...
你是想
Break up, of course.
分手啊
While our relationship
趁着咱俩这段关系
is still at a surface level,
还没有深入
let's part on good terms.
好聚好散
Why?
为什么
You don't really need
你应该不需要
me to explain
我给你科普
Dairui's rules
代瑞
about office romances, right?
对办公室恋情的态度吧
You just got appointed
你不声不响地
as the head of our section.
就空降到这边来
What if our relationship
万一我们俩的关系
gets exposed?
被发现了
One of us will have to go.
那只能二选一
Who do you think
你觉得
will be the one to leave?
走的那个人会是谁呢
You are
你
personally appointed by the president.
是行长亲自挑选的经理
As for me,
我呢
I'm just some temp worker
是一个被辞掉了
who could be laid off anytime
都不需要什么理由的
without any solid reasons.
临时工
It's pretty clear, right?
那用脚趾头都能想明白
It will definitely
到时候走的那个人
be me.
肯定是我呀
Rather than living each day
与其每天过着
in constant anxiety,
提心吊胆的日子
not knowing when
不知道这颗炸弹
our secret will be exposed,
什么时候爆炸
I think it's better if
那还不如自己
I end this relationship myself.
结束这段关系
So this is what you're worried about.
原来你担心的是这个
Even if you didn't ask me today,
就算今天你不问我
I would bring it
我也会把这件事情
up.
告诉你
And this is an offer
而且这是行长
from the president.
对我提出的邀约
I haven't made a final
我也没有最终
decision yet.
做出一个决定
The whole thing
整件事情
is still up in the air.
都是一个没有定论的事
Tu Xiaoning,
但是涂筱柠
you want to break up with me
你因为一件
because of something
没有定论的事情
still undecided?
就要选择跟我分手
Is this truly how you
这就是你对待
perceive our relationship?
我们之间的关系的态度
Don't you think this is rather hasty?
就这么草率吗
I...
我
What's going on?
怎么了
A bone?
是不是卡到了
Stay still.
别动
The key, the key!
钥匙 钥匙
Come on! Hurry!
快 快 快
Why?
怎么了
Hurry up!
我不知道怎么了 快点
Does it hurt?
这样疼不疼
What's wrong?
怎么了
A fish bone got stuck in her throat.
好像卡着鱼刺了
Some vinegar should help.
那喝点醋就好了
There's still
对了
half a steamed bun left from breakfast.
早餐还剩了半拉馒头呢
It could damage her esophagus.
可能会损伤到食道
I'll take her to the hospital.
我带筱柠去医院
Don't worry, let's go.
你们放心 走
Alright, alright.
那行 那行
Hurry up and go!
赶快去吧 赶快去吧
OK.
好
It hurts!
疼
Miss,
护士
I'd like to know this is...
我问问这是
It's a laryngoscopy.
做喉镜啊
By using this, we could
这样能更清楚地
see what's going on in her esophagus.
看到食道情况
Will it hurt with
做喉镜这么长的管子
such a long tube?
会不会很疼啊
We'll apply anesthetic.
会喷麻药的
The one next door has an injury.
隔壁那个是外伤
It's a different case.
和她情况不一样
I've never seen a family member
第一次见家属
more nervous than the patient.
比患者还紧张的
Don't worry,
放心吧
it's nothing serious.
没什么大事
We rely on you.
那麻烦你了
Tu Xiaoning, right?
涂筱柠是吧
Come here.
过来吧
Alright.
好了
The bone has been removed.
鱼刺已经取出来了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
The doctor said
医生说了
the puncture wasn't deep.
刺扎得不深
It'll be alright in a couple of days.
过两天就能好
Alright.
好了
Stop crying.
不哭了
I'm not crying.
谁哭了
It's just a physiological reaction.
我这生理反应
It's from the throat being irritated.
捅嗓子捅的
Yeah, it's indeed physiological.
确实是生理性的
You'll be fine soon.
一会儿就好了
Your husband really cares about you.
你老公可真心疼你
Let's go.
走吧
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Here, have some water.
来 先喝口水
Thank you.
谢谢
You're my wife.
我们之间的关系
No need for thanks.
就不用说这些了
- You... - You...
你
You go first.
你先说
About the transfer to section one,
调去拓展一部的事儿
I think I owe you
我觉得我有必要
an explanation.
解释一下
The president
行长他
wants me to lead it
让我过来
for a reason.
是有原因的
Mr Xing from section two
二部的小邢
just landed a huge project days ago.
前两天刚接了个大项目
He's on a roll.
风头正盛
The headquarters wanna
总行的意思呢
merge the two sections
是要把两个部门合并
and have him manage it.
让他来管
The leadership for section one
而一部现在的问题是
is now absent.
群龙无首
Jing and Fanggang are competing.
饶静跟赵方刚搞内斗
Also,
而且
many people are quitting.
不断有人辞职
It can be described as a
可以说是个
tricky mess.
棘手的烂摊子
At this moment,
这个时候
I have no better choice
我除了你
than you.
没有更好的人选
Just one year.
就一年
We're
总行
only given one year
就给了我们一年的时间
to reorganize section one.
来整顿一部
Once the time is up,
时间一到
I won't force you to remain in there.
老师绝不会再为难你
As for the Compliance Dept,
至于合规部那边呢
don't sweat it,
你不用担心
I'll let them know about it.
我会跟他们打好招呼
I won't make you look bad.
不会让你难做
Sir,
不过老师
I've still
我还是
got a question for you.
有一个问题想问您
Go ahead.
你问
Why are you so insistent
您为什么那么坚持
on keeping section one?
要保留拓展一部
It has many small and micro enterprises
这个一部的客户里边啊
among the clients.
有很多小微企业
Once it get merged with section two,
一旦被二部合并呢
this business will be greatly reduced.
就会大幅消减这项业务
But it's precisely these enterprises
但恰恰是这些小企业
that could address many
能解决很多老百姓的
employment issues.
就业问题
So,
所以呢
I just want to do my best
我就想尽力
to keep it.
能留一留
Got it.
我明白了
I'll think it through
回去之后
after I get home,
我好好考虑一下
and get back to you ASAP.
尽快给您答复
So,
所以说想要
keeping section one
保住拓展一部
is no simple task.
其实没那么容易
The terms set by the headquarters
总行开出的条件
require a 50% increase in performance.
业绩要上涨百分之五十
This will be an impossible task.
这是不可能完成的任务
Isn't that putting you in a tough spot?
这不是难为人吗
But,
不过
you are willing to take it, right?
你还是想去的
After all, you didn't say no.
毕竟你没有直接拒绝
Right?
对吧
Actually, I hesitated
其实我会犹豫
for two reasons.
是有两方面的原因
The first one is
第一个原因是
the president has indeed helped me.
行长对我确实有恩
After graduating from college,
大学毕业了
I wanted to study abroad.
我想要出国留学
But publication in core journals
但只有在核心期刊上
is a prerequisite
发表过论文的人
for scholarship eligibility.
才能够申请公费奖学金
After mine was published,
那时候论文发表完之后
without my knowledge,
在我不知情的情况之下
my first author status
我一作的身份
was taken by an associate professor.
被副教授给占了
The president,
行长
risking offending colleagues,
他冒着得罪人的风险
fought for me in the matter.
为我据理力争
He even personally wrote a letter
然后他还亲自写信
to the journal.
给到了期刊
That's how I regained my authorship.
才帮我拿回了署名
He also
同时
helped me
也帮助我
secure the scholarship.
申请到了奖学金
So,
所以
you're doing this to repay a favor.
你是为了报恩
What's your second reason?
那第二个原因呢
Because of
第二个原因
my mother's condition.
是我妈妈的病
I need money.
我需要钱
What happened to her?
阿姨她怎么了
She has two new
我妈她多了两处
distant metastases.
远端转移
The last medication was used for too long,
之前的药用了太久
and the tumor has developed resistance.
出现了耐药性
Now we can only use
现在只能用
the latest foreign products.
最新的国外产品
Those targeted therapies
那些靶向药
are not covered by insurance.
又是纯自费
The cost will be significant.
一年下来开销会很大
So, for me, leading section one
所以拓展一部对我来说
would be a high-risk,
是一个高风险
but high-reward opportunity.
但是高回报的地方
I'd like to take a chance.
我想要搏一把
These two reasons
这两个原因
sound solid.
听着都非常合理
If I were you,
如果我是你的话
I would also take this chance.
我也会去拓展一部的
Xiaoning,
但是筱柠
I did intend to
我说要跟你商量
discuss this with you.
不是说说而已
I won't force you to accept it either.
我也不会强迫你去接受
You're my wife.
我们是要结婚的关系
And I understand
你所有的担忧
all your concerns.
我都能理解
If I really take this offer,
如果说我真的去了一部
it will definitely cause you
肯定会给你
some trouble.
带来一些困扰
But I truly was not
但我真的不是
disregarding your work.
不考虑你的工作
It wasn't a placement on your team
也不是直接空降
without prior notice either.
也不说一声
I don't want you
等真出了
to leave alone
什么问题的时候
after something goes wrong.
让你一个人离开
The Compliance Dept
合规部
was my first choice.
是我最初的选择
I genuinely enjoy my current job,
我很喜欢我现在的工作
so I don't feel the urge to transfer.
所以并非一定要去一部
You can be assured of that.
这点你可以放心
There's been a lot happening recently.
最近发生的事情有点多
This has made it difficult
有很多事情
for me to clarify the situation.
我还没有想清楚
We all need
我们还是各自冷静一下
more time.
想明白了以后再说吧
Alright.
好
But please don't take too long, OK?
但是别冷静太久好吗
Sir,
老师
are you asleep?
您休息了吗
Hello, sir.
喂 老师
Yuheng,
昱恒
have you made up your mind?
你这是 考虑好了
Yes, I have.
我考虑好了老师
I'm sorry to let you down.
让您失望了
I wanna
我想
stay in the
我还是决定
Compliance Dept.
要留在合规部
If there's anything else in the future
如果以后有其他
that I could assist you with,
我能帮得上忙的
I will certainly give my best.
我一定会尽力
Thanks, sir.
谢谢老师
I will find a way to cover
我母亲的费用
my mom's medical expenses.
我会再想办法
Given his situation,
以他的处境
transferring to section one
答应调到拓展一部
would certainly be the wise choice.
才是明智的选择吧
He shouldn't have given up
不该为了我
the change for my sake.
放弃这个机会
Last night, I didn't fully grasp
昨天晚上我没弄清楚
the reasons behind your transfer,
你调职的原委
and I ended up losing my temper.
就跟你发脾气
That was my fault,
是我的不对
I'm 27 years old.
我今年二十七了
I no longer have the
已经没有二十岁的
enthusiasm of my twenties
意气风发
or the luxury of making mistakes.
和试错的机会
This is my first job
这是我毕业后的
after graduation.
第一份工作
I haven't been made permanent in 3 years,
三年没转正
and finding a new job will be tougher.
再找工作会更难
To be honest,
说实话
I've been...
我
under a lot of pressure.
也很有压力
I don't want anything
我不希望有任何事情
to interfere with my work.
影响到我的工作
I understand your concerns.
你说的我理解
Actually, last night,
其实昨天晚上
I clarified everything with the president.
我已经跟行长说清楚了
But I don't want you to give up
但是我不需要你为了我
this opportunity to lead section one
放弃去拓展一部
because of me.
这个机会
I would feel stressed.
我会很有压力的
I thought about it all night last night.
我昨天晚上想了一晚上
How about
要不
we make an agreement?
我们订个协议吧
Agreement?
协议
Yes.
嗯
Let's set a one-year term.
以一年为期限
We'll let our skills do the talking.
我们靠本事说话
Since if we get exposed,
要是被发现了的话
one of us must resign.
不能同时留下
Then,
那
we can each set
各自给各自订个
a KPI for ourselves.
关键绩效指标
Whoever meets
完成这个
the KPI
关键绩效指标的人
will remain.
就留下
The one who fails will leave.
失败的人走
How about that?
你觉得怎么样
Sounds like
听起来
an earnout agreement.
是一个对赌协议
Exactly.
对呀
Are you serious about this?
当真吗
I am.
当真
I want to challenge myself.
我也想逼自己一把
Besides,
再说
I don't think I'm going to lose.
我不觉得自己一定会输
But
只不过
regarding the marriage registration...
领证这件事情
Our relationship
我们最多也就
should progress
以结婚为前提
with marriage in mind.
继续相处吧
Sure.
嗯
One year it is.
那就一年
If within a year,
如果在一年的时间里
you find me
你对我
satisfactory,
考察合格
and if we can
而且我们的工作
keep both of our jobs,
各自有着落的话
then we will get married for real.
那就正式结婚
Alright.
好
As for my parents,
父母那边的话
we still need to keep
还是要维持
things as they are.
现在这个状态
I don't want them to be concerned.
我怕他们会担心
Absolutely.
一定
Don't worry.
放心吧
During this year,
在这一年的时间里
I will definitely be a
我一定会是一个
competent rival.
合格的对手
I won't be slacking off either.
我也一点不会怠慢的
I've already drafted the agreement.
这个我已经写好了
Within a year,
我涂筱柠一年内呢
I must be converted to permanent
需要在代瑞拓展一部
employee in section one,
成功转正
and
并且
secure ten million in deposits.
拉到一千万存款
Alright.
好
Then within a year,
那我一年时间内
I'll double the performance of section one.
把拓展一部的业绩翻倍
Isn't that a bit excessive?
不用玩这么大吧
Since it's an earnout agreement,
既然是对赌协议
I need to show some sincerity.
当然要拿出一些诚意来
But that is
那这个是完全
an impossible task.
不可能完成的任务呀
For others,
在别人那里
it might not be achievable.
或许不一定
But for me,
但在我这儿
it's workable.
有可能
Then I'll adjust my target too.
那我也改一下吧
Fifty million.
五千万
Are you sure? It's a huge risk.
确定要赌这么大
I can't let you suffer a disadvantage.
我不能让你吃亏呀
We need to be fair!
公平
So during this year,
那这一年内
we need to work hard in section one
我们要在拓展一部
to fulfill our agreement,
好好努力完成协议
and avoid causing trouble for each other.
不给彼此添麻烦
Absolutely.
一定
Good luck.
加油
Hello.
喂
I'll be there shortly.
我马上就到
Yuheng previously worked
昱恒以前呢
in the Compliance Dept
是在内控合规部
responsible for internal auditing.
做监察工作的
He is familiar to many of you
跟我们很多同事啊
and has had
都认识
interactions with most of you.
都打过交道
So I believe that
所以我相信呢
you will definitely
你们一定能
work as a team and
配合默契
help section one out of its difficulties.
把拓展部带出困境
Do you have that confidence?
有信心没有
Yes, we do!
有信心
Fanggang,
赵经理
you and Jing are both
你跟饶经理在业务方面
experienced veterans.
都算是前辈了
I hope you can cooperate with
以后还希望你们能
each other and work as a team.
多配合 多协助
Yes, sir.
行长
You can rest assured.
您放心
In our section one,
我们拓展一部
we focus on
主打的就是
unity and teamwork.
团结一心
Mr Ji,
纪总
if you need anything,
未来您要有什么需要
I'll be available 24/7.
我二十四小时在线
Thank you, Mr Zhao.
辛苦赵经理了
No problem.
客气
Sir, ease your mind.
行长您放心吧
I will also
我也会做好
fulfill my duties.
分内的事情的
Great, that sounds reassuring.
那我就放心了
Whoa, so early.
这么早
Mr President.
行长
- Li Xiang. - Xiaoning.
李想 小涂
Your name tag.
工牌
The meeting
开会
has been going on for half an hour.
半个小时了
Where have you been?
干吗去了
I had a diarrhea.
我闹肚子
Yuheng,
昱恒
from now on,
那以后
I will leave section one
拓展一部的重担
to you.
就交给你了
Don't worry, sir.
放心吧行长
I will definitely do my best.
一定做好
I'm leaving.
那我先走了
You guys continue.
你们继续
Take care.
行长您慢走啊
Have a safe trip back, sir.
路上注意安全行长
Goodbye.
再见
Take care, sir.
慢走行长
Later.
再见 再见
It's OK.
没关系
Please sit down.
大家坐下聊
Let's start by
那我们先
getting to know each other.
互相认识一下吧
My name is Ji Yuheng.
我叫纪昱恒
I previously worked in
之前就职于
the Compliance Dept.
代瑞银行的内控合规部
In the past few months,
过去这几个月
we should have run into each other.
我们之间应该有过照面
From today onward,
从今天起
we are a team.
我们就是同事了
Section one
之前拓展一部
has indeed faced some challenges before.
确实存在一些问题
Now, while the issues
现在问题
have been resolved.
虽然已经解决了
They have still taken a toll on us.
但也是元气大伤
I hope
我希望
that in the near future,
未来的一段时间里
we can prepare together
我们可以一起
for tough challenges ahead.
做好打硬仗的准备
Let's start with me.
那从我这儿开始吧
I'll introduce myself.
我先自我介绍一下
Rao Jing,
饶静
a senior account manager for 8 years.
高级客户经理八年
Nice to meet you.
你好饶经理
I'm Zhao Fanggang.
赵方刚
I've been a senior account manager
高级客户经理
for 7.5 years.
七年半
I'm Xu Li,
许力
an account manager,
客户经理
five years.
五年
Liu Xiaomang,
刘晓芒
account manager for 3.5 years.
客户经理三年半
I'm Shen Shuyao.
沈书姚
I've been an
可以叫我小姚
account manager for 3 years.
客户经理三年
Now it's my turn, right?
到我了是吧
I'm Li Xiang,
李想
an account manager,
客户经理
for 6 years.
六年
I'm Yao Shiyun.
姚诗芸
An account manager
大家都叫我叫大姚
for 3 years and 2 months.
客户经理三年零两个月
I'm Zhang Xiangdong.
张向东
An account manager for 5 years.
客户经理五年
I am
我是
an assistant to account managers.
客户经理助理
I haven't been made permanent yet.
还没有转正
My name is
我叫
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
So among us,
那在座的
except for Tu Xiaoning,
除了涂筱柠之外
everyone here has over 3 years
都有三年以上的
of experience as account managers.
客户经理的经历
So in terms of work experience
所以无论是工作经验
and qualifications in the industry,
还是从业时间上来讲
you all are my seniors.
都算是我的前辈
From now on,
那之后
I look forward to working with you.
就承蒙大家的关照
Mr Ji,
纪总
you're being
您太谦虚了
overly modest.
我们哪敢当啊
Nice to meet you all.
初次见面
Let's all go out to eat together.
今天晚上我做东
I'm buying.
请大家一起吃个饭吧
Mr Ji,
纪总
since you are new,
您刚来可能还
you might not be familiar with
对我们拓展部
the daily business here.
不太清楚
We don't have
我们呢
a typical 9-to-5 schedule.
没有朝九晚五
After work,
下了班之后
we still need to entertain clients.
还需要去陪客户应酬
So,
所以
we really don't have time
实在是没有时间
to join you for dinner.
陪您吃饭
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Oh yeah, Xu Li,
对了那个 许力呀
aren't we meeting
咱们晚上
with Mr Li tonight?
不是跟李总约了
That's right.
对
We can't make it either.
我们也不行
Sorry about that.
不好意思啊
We have plans tonight as well.
我们今天晚上也有事
That's fine.
没关系
So,
那
maybe another time.
我们再抽时间吧
I won't hold up everyone.
不耽误大家工作
Let's wrap up the meeting.
散会吧
Right.
对
Be patient.
有点耐心
Could you pass
你把那个
the... um...
那个 那个
contract with Guangcai
强力光彩的合同
to me?
拿给我看看
Ms Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠同学
are you currently in
你最近在谈一场
a new relationship?
很新的恋爱吗
Not only is it based on actual marriage,
不但以结婚为前提
but you've also become
而且还和纪昱恒
Ji Yuheng's...
成了上下
Don't mention his name.
别叫他名字
What if someone hears it?
万一被人听见怎么办
Don't worry about it.
你别担心了
Office romance,
这办公室恋情
while fraught with risks,
虽然危机四伏
is also quite exciting.
但也足够惊险刺激啊
We are in a clear and honest
我们俩是清清白白的
relationship.
恋爱关系
Yeah, sure,
谁信啊
clear and honest.
清白的恋爱关系
I'm serious.
真的
We truly haven't
我们俩真的
gotten there yet.
没到你想的那一步
You kidding?
你开什么玩笑
You're both in your 20s.
二十多岁的激情男女
Is he incapable in that department?
他那方面不会是不行吧
Nonsense.
你说啥
What's incapable?
什么不行啊
It's nothing.
没什么
Mr Ji.
纪总
Is that all you're having for lunch?
午餐就吃这些啊
Their instant food are quite good.
他们家暖食挺好吃的
You should give them a shot next time.
要不你下次也尝尝
You're really good at role-playing.
你俩这角色扮演
Very convincing.
真是相当到位
Alright then.
那行
I'll leave you girls to it.
不打扰你们吃饭了
Drink it while it's hot.
趁热喝
What's this?
这什么呀
I'm done.
我吃完了
Clean it up for me.
帮我收一下啊
You're leaving already?
你这就走啊
Ms Rao has been in there
饶经理进去
for quite a while.
这么长时间了
Why hasn't she come out yet?
怎么还不出来
Looking for me?
有事吗
No.
没事啊
Then get ready for a meeting.
没事收拾一下开会吧
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
on your toes. We have a meeting.
精神点开会了
What meeting can we have at noon?
大中午的开什么会啊
Why don't you
那要不你
just go and ask Mr Ji?
直接进去问纪总
I think he will give you
我想纪总会给你一个
a satisfactory answer.
满意地答复的
Also,
还有啊
the lunch break
这个休息时间呢
has already ended 3 minutes ago.
已经过了三分钟了
I heard that Mr Ji
听说咱们纪总
doesn't like waiting.
不喜欢等人
A new broom sweeps clean.
新官上任三把火呦
And the first sweep
这第一把火
is on me.
就点着我屁股了
Alright.
行
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
what new tricks this amateur
这个业务门外汉
will come up with.
要烧出什么新花样
Mr Ji.
纪总
He really likes the mint ones, huh?
这么喜欢薄荷啊
Let's use this one.
咱们用这个吧
My parents say the mint ones
我爸妈说用薄荷的
makes teeth cleaner.
刷牙刷得干净
Most people like it.
大多数人都喜欢
And you don't have to accommodate me.
而且你不用迁就我的
I'm not picky.
其实我也不挑
I just think that
我只是想着
every corner of the house
家里的每一个地方
should reflect what we both like.
都是我们彼此喜欢的
Then let's
那就
get them both.
两盒都买吧
That will come with 20% off.
两盒还八折呢